Do you enjoy working?
你喜欢工作吗？
Does the prospect of a day in the office fill you with excitement or dread?
想到在办公室的一天，你是充满兴奋还是恐惧？
And when you're at your desk do you spend your time clock-watching – longing for the moment when it's time to switch off your computer and head for home?
当你坐在办公桌前时，是否会一直看时间——渴望着关掉电脑回家的那一刻？
For some of us, we start the working week on Monday and count the days until Friday when the weekend begins and we have a break from the daily grind.
对我们中的一些人来说，从周一开始工作周，数着日子直到周五周末开始，从日常苦差中解脱。
But does it have to be this way?
但必须这样吗？
Hopefully, working brings us some pleasure. And there's the chance of career development and a pay rise.
希望工作能给我们带来一些乐趣，还有职业发展和加薪的机会。
But surely there is a life outside the office to be enjoyed.
但办公室之外肯定有值得享受的生活。
And if life is for living, then maybe we should get on living it!
如果生活是为了活着，那我们或许应该好好生活！
Maybe that's why some people are questioning whether a five-day working week is right for employees and employers alike?
也许这就是为什么有人质疑每周五天工作制是否对员工和雇主都合适？
It's something BBC journalist Ashitha Nagesh has been investigating.
这是BBC记者阿西塔・纳格什一直在调查的问题。
She says that although technology is supposed to make our working lives easier, giving us more leisure time, "tech has arguably had the opposite effect - it's enabled an 'always-on' culture that means even when you go home, the work doesn't stop."
她说，尽管科技本应让工作生活更轻松，给我们更多闲暇时间，“但科技可能产生了相反的效果——它催生了一种‘永远在线’的文化，意味着即使回家，工作也没停止。”
It seems we need to do something to find a better work-life balance.
看来我们需要做些什么来寻找更好的工作与生活平衡。
The company Prospect Guardian trialled a four-day week earlier this year and reportedly found workers were less stressed and had a better work-life balance when they had an extra day off in the week, but were still paid for five days.
今年早些时候，Prospect Guardian公司试行每周四天工作制，据说，当员工们每周多休一天但仍拿五天工资时，压力更小，工作与生活平衡更好。
This, in turn, apparently meant they were more productive on the days that they were in the office.
这反过来显然意味着他们工作日办公效率更高。
In the UK, the Green Party is calling for a four-day week, which would help people's "well-being".
在英国，绿党呼吁实行每周四天工作制，这将有助于人们的“福祉”。
Co-leader Sian Berry told the BBC work-life balance was "in crisis" and claims that "people with more fulfilling work and more free time could be more productive".
联合领导人西恩・贝瑞告诉BBC，工作与生活平衡处于“危机中”，并声称“工作更有成就感、空闲时间更多的人可能更高效”。
A shorter working week is also believed to better for your health.
更短的工作周也被认为有益健康。
Research has found that working long hours increases the chance of work-related stress, depression and anxiety.
研究发现，长时间工作更有可能增加与工作相关的压力、抑郁和焦虑。
And a project by Project:Time Off and GfK found it was the millennial generation who felt particularly stressed and overworked and were reluctant to use up their annual leave.
Project:Time Off和GfK的一个项目发现，千禧一代尤其感到压力大、工作过度，且不愿用完年假。
So with evidence that we can be more productive and healthier, maybe a four-day week will become a reality for all of us.
因此，有证据表明我们可以更高效、更健康，也许每周四天工作制将成为我们所有人的现实。
The next problem would be deciding what to do with that extra free time!
下一个问题是决定如何利用额外的空闲时间！